# TIMOTHY COCA

DATAANALYST

Commented [1]: This is looking really good overall

# CONTACT

(615) 557-7548

9 3325 Dumas Dr, Nashville, TN 37211

# **STORY**

I am a hardworking problem solver with an affinity for discovering and clearly representing the answers to complex data questions. My past experience allows me to excel at collaborating with a team towards an intuitive solution.

Approaching new challenges with passion and grit is a hallmark of my work background, and I strive to learn from my experiences.



www.linkedin.com/in/timot



https://github.com/tmcoca

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Data Analytics Certification**

Nashville Software School Nashville, TN | 2022

#### Molecular Biology (earned credits)

Fisk University

Nashville, TN | 2016 - 2018

#### Biochemistry & Philosophy (earned credits)

Lipscomb University Nashville, TN | 2015 - 2016

## **SKILLS**

Excel (pivot tables, lookups)

SQL

Python

Tableau

Power BI

Project Management

Strategy Planning

Agile Methodology

Kanban Boards

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### Data Analyst Certification

Nashville Software School | Nashville, TN | January 2022 - April 2022

Intensive part-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

Lahman Baseball Project: used SQL to perform an exploratory analysis of a large dataset to answer key questions (involved CTEs, joins, window functions, and subqueries)

UN Data Project: used Python to explore a database from the UN and provide insightful analysis on country GDP and internet use (involved importing packages, dataframe merges, and the creation of graphs and charts using matplotlib and seaborn)

Olympics Dashboard: created interactive dashboard for analyzing Olympics results quickly

#### Shift Leader / Instructor / Coach

Climb Nashville | Nashville, TN | 2016 - PRESENT

Grew into multiple positions of increasing impact throughout my time here. My work at Climb Nashville has taught me important lessons about working in a team, spearheading the development of programs for the community, and approaching all the work I do with passion.

Shift Leader - managed desk staff and headed daily operations for the gym. Instructor - developed class curriculums related to fitness, provided personal lessons/training, and led group outdoor trips where the focus was providing an incredible experience in rock climbing while keeping everyone safe. Coach - was the head coach for the Vanderbilt collegiate climbing team as well as coaching the local competitive youth team. Propagated a mentality of being comfortable with mistakes and using them to improve through effort and focus.

## Telecommunications Infrastructure Safety Inspector

JAG Resources | Nashville, TN | 2021 - 2022

Traveled across the U.S. to different contracted tower sites, providing analysis and important safety data related to needed repairs and installations.

Generated \$100,000+ in commissions for the company. Worked alongside a partner, requiring extensive collaboration and teamwork.

Commented [2]: I would title it as "Data Analyst Apprentice" here. Also, can add bullets between the NSS description and the projects if you'd like. See the example under "Resume Resources" and see if you'd like to add any of those.

Commented [3]: I would just make this a bullet point

